ADAM ONISHI

WEB DEVELOPER & DESIGNER

ABOUT ME

I am a self motivated and expert front-end & PHP developer, working with the latest and most exciting web technologies. I enjoy an active role contributing to the web community via writing and created the extremely successful web events and community sites 12 Devs and 12 Devs of Xmas.

I'm a regular public speaker having spoken at a variety of events and conferences, from monthly meet ups, Front End London and London Web Standards, through to international conferences including the New York Sass Conf and Devs Love Bacon in London. During 2013 I wrote a book with Apress - Pro WordPress Theme Development.

My ultimate career goal is to always be doing things that interest me and aiming to make a difference to the web.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Front-end Developer - Architect (June 2013 - present)

- Responsible for managing a team of developers (workloads and job progression).
- Helped win one of the largest projects Architect had taken on; the rebuild and launch of one of Unilever's biggest brands: Persil.
- Lead developer on a large project WordPress Multisite, Sass (and Compass), and JavaScript/jQuery architecture.
- Responsible for code reviews on front-end code.
- Responsible for formalising the front-end processes:
 - created a front-end boilerplate,
 - introduced a front-end code style guide,
 - helped bring in code review practices.
- Helped create a more positive attitude towards staff education and training, resulting in a more formalised process.

Front-end Developer - Big Fish (Aug 2012 - June 2013)

- Dedicated front-end developer working on a variety of websites for Big Fish's clients.
- Worked with up to date technologies including canvas and JavaScript to keep the client's web presence as up-to-date as possible.
- Lead developer on the company's first canvas game.
- Pushed to bring responsive web design into the toolkit for the web team.

Web Developer - One Ltd. Aug 2009 - August 2012

- Lead developer for front-end and Wordpress projects.
- Worked closely with the designers to create the best possible websites.
- Managed the development team and web project scheduling.
- Created a **Wordpress boilerplate**, which at the time all of our websites were based upon.
- BBQ chef and occasional cake baker.

While there I **initiated** a **large review of the practices at One**, introducing more structure and maintainability through the use of tools like **LESS**, **Git**, **and Codekit**, as well as emphasising a better collaborative environment.

CONT...

SKILLS

Everyday use:

- Well structured.

- Sass & Compass

accessible HTML

- Mobile first
- Accessibility
- Performance - PHP
- WordPress

Would like to do more of:

- Design
- Node
- Meteor
- Angular
- Laravel
- WebRTC

- Grunt
- Git
- JavaScript

- CSS/CSS3

- iQuery
- Progressive enhancement
- Responsive web design

EDUCATION

BSc (hons) Computer Science - Oxford Brookes University. 2005 - 2010

Graduated with First Class degree with honours. Final year project entailed building an e-commerce CMS in OOPHP. Spent a gap year in Australia (07-08).

BTEC National Diploma for IT Practitioners - Banbury College. 2002 - 2004

Achieved triple grade merit.

8 GCSEs. Drayton School, Banbury. 1997 - 2002

INTERESTS

Working on interesting web projects out of the office. Attending web conferences, getting the opportunity to meet new people and take on new ideas.

Cycling, both commuting and regular sportives.

Food, both cooking and eating. If I hadn't been so interested in programming I'd have probably become a pastry chef.

CONTACT

Telphone: 07412 555 187

onishiweb@gmail.com Email: Website: adamonishi.co.uk

Twitter: @onishiweb Github:

github.com/onishiweb Speakerdeck: speakerdeck.com/onishiweb

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST.